Kufr means disbelief,
rejection and denial of Islam
after it has been properly presented and explained.
Islamic scholars usually refer to verse 136 of Sura an-Nisa
for the definition of Kufr, where it says:
[Arabic recitation]
"Anyone who denies Allah, His angels, His books, His Apostles, and the Day of judgment..." (An-Nisaa?: 136)
There are literally hundreds of verses about Kufr in the Qur'an
that make it abundantly clear that not believing
is a terrible crime
that will be punished by eternal and excruciating torture.
These are just a few:
"Those who reject Faith in the Signs of Allah will suffer the severest penalty, and Allah is Exalted in Might, Lord of Retribution" (3:4)
"Those who reject the Book and the (revelations) with which We sent our messengers:
soon shall they know. When the yokes (shall be) round their necks, and the chains;
they shall be dragged along. In the boiling fetid fluid:
then in the Fire shall they be burned." (40:70-72)
But why is disbelief such a terrible crime?
What exactly has the disbeliever done to warrant such appalling punishment?
Belief is not something we have complete control over
and one cannot simply choose to believe something
that one finds unbelievable.
For example we cannot choose to believe that grass is made of chocolate
nor can we believe that dolphins live in trees.
There are other issues that are not so clear-cut
where we have less evidence for example.
In these cases there maybe an element of doubt
whether to believe or to disbelieve.
Though that still doesn't mean it's a simple matter of a choice.
For example if I told you there were invisible fairies
living in my back garden and that I know this because
my great, great, great grandfather left me a note
which he got from them saying:
"Hello, we are faries
and we live in your back-garden."
Some might argue that there is an element of doubt here
since there is no conclusive evidence that faries don't exist
and there are actually people who believe in them.
But in such a case we don't simply choose what to believe.
Each one of us weighs up the evidence as we see it.
We compare the arguments we've heard
and filter this through the our cultural references or emotional responses
that are are peculiar to us as a person.
We then either believe or disbelieve based on that.
Whether it turns out that fairies do exist,
it would be totally unreasonable to torture anyone
who reached the wrong conclusion.
At worst they would be guilty of nothing more
than mistaken or faulty reasoning.
In other words, belief and disbelief
has nothing to do with being an evil or bad person
and no one in their right mind would say that people
with faulty reasoning deserve to be punished.
Some equate disbelief with being ungrateful,
but Christians, Hindus and Deists of all types would argue
that they are very grateful to God.
Atheists, too, would argue that they are grateful.
though they direct their gratitude towards the person
they perceive as responsible
rather than a god they don't believe exists.
So these people are not guilty of ingratitude.
But perhaps the most ridiculous explanation
is that kufr means people
who know Islam is true, but hide it.
Kufr comes from a root meaning to cover up and hide.
So they argue it implies a willful and malicious intent.
People who know Islam is true
but intentionally hide the truth.
If this were true, then they must be insane.
No person of sound mind would knowingly
choose to be tortured in the most agonising way
for all eternity.
So if this is the case,
then Allah will be torturing mad people.
It is amazing how much scorn, contempt and hatred
the Qur'an directs towards Kufr
and as a result how emotive the words Kufr and Kafir are for Muslims.
Yet when you actually get past this emotion
there really is no logical reason
why disbelief should be considered such a horrendous crime.
Even if Islam were true
the fact that the Qur'an spends so much time condemning disbelievers
to the most obscene eternal torture
it only serves to emphasize that it is not.
♪ Music: "Him" by Lily Allen ♪